A Guide to the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) records FA084
Rockefeller Archive Center
- General Information - Data and Research, 1937-1976; 5; 7.22 Cubic Feet 19 letter document boxes
  - Data and Research - Commissions - Inter American Commercial Arbitration Commission, 1961-1968 (Box 84, Folder 654)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, newsletter. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - General Information - Communism, 1960-1969 (Box 84, Folder 655)
    Correspondence, newsletter, article, catalogue, memorandum, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Data Processing, 1969 (Box 85, Folder 656)
    Program, report, memorandum, correspondence, brochure, magazine. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Directories (A-Z), 1968 (Box 85, Folder 657)
  - General Information - Drugs and Narcotics, 1970-1971 (Box 85, Folder 658)
    Correspondence, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Education, 1968-1971 (Box 85, Folder 659)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, brochure, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Electronic Data Processing, 1967-1969 (Box 85, Folder 660)
    Correspondence, magazine, article, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Energy, 1972-1975 (Box 85, Folder 661)
    Article, brochure, news clipping, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Environment, 1969-1976 (Box 85, Folder 662)
    Correspondence, news clipping, report, memorandum, map, bulletin, chart. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Environment - Brochures, 1970-1976 (Box 85, Folder 663, Box 86)
    Correspondence, article, annual report, newsletter, press release, catalogue, brochure, report, bulletin, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Fertilizers, 1965-1966 (Box 86, Folder 664)
    Brochure, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Financial and Leasing Companies (A-K), 1959-1975 (Box 86, Folder 665)
    Correspondence, memorandum, article, magazine, report, summary, program, news clipping, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Financial and Leasing Companies (L-Z), 1961-1975 (Box 86, Folder 666)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, proposal, memorandum, brochure, annual report, prospectus. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Fishing Industry, 1973 (Box 86, Folder 667)
  - General Information - Fishing Industry - Shellfish, 1970 (Box 86, Folder 668)
  - Data and Research - Food, 1955-1974 (Box 87, Folder 669)
    Newsletter, report, journal, article, memorandum, magazine, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Food Processors, 1967-1972 (Box 87, Folder 670)
    News clipping, memorandum, brochure, catalogue, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Protein Foods, 1968-1972 (Box 87, Folder 671)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, memorandum, telex. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Protein Foods - Brochures, 1968-1970 (Box 87, Folder 672, Box 88, Folder 672A)
    Report, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Grains - Corn, 1954-1970 (Box 88, Folder 673)
    Correspondence, news clipping, bulletin, report, journal. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Rice, 1949-1967 (Box 88, Folder 674)
    Correspondence, news clipping, memorandum, brochure, journal. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Grains - Rice Reports - Mehrlich, Ferdinand P., 1949 (Box 88, Folder 675)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, cablegram, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - Data and Research - Grains - Rice Reports - Efferson, J. Norman, 1949 (Box 88, Folder 676)
    Report, circular. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Grains - Wheat, 1969-1971 (Box 89, Folder 677)
  - General Information - Hogs, 1966-1968 (Box 89, Folder 678)
    Brochure, report, journal, bulletin, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Human Relations, 1965 (Box 89, Folder 679)
  - Data and Research - Hydroponics - Brig. Gen. Herman Feldman, Rob. L. Luckhmardt, 1946-1967 (Box 89, Folder 680)
    Correspondence, memorandum, brochure, manual. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Insurance, 1975 (Box 89, Folder 681)
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds, 1963-1972 (Box 89, Folder 682)
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds - Investors Overseas Services (IOS), 1968-1973 (Box 89, Folder 683)
    Correspondence, news clipping, telegram, memorandum, magazine, prospectus, annual report, report, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds - Investors Overseas Services (IOS) #2, 1969-1971 (Box 89, Folder 684, Box 90, Folder 684A)
    Prospectus, annual report, report, news clipping, magazine. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds, 1969-1971 (Box 90, Folder 685)
    Correspondence, report, quarterly, annual report, balance, prospectus. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Investments - Foreign Divestments, 1969-1970 (Box 90, Folder 686)
    Report, memorandum, journal. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Foreign Investments - Multinational Corporation, 1969-1976 (Box 90, Folder 687)
    Correspondence, brochure, bulletin, draft, news clipping, summary, report, article. Documents in this folder are in English and Portuguese.
  - General Information - Foreign Investments, 1969-1976 (Box 91, Folder 688)
    Correspondence, bulletin, memorandum, program, report, proposal, brochure, speech, article, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - General Information - Foreign Investments - Multinational Corporation (Bulletins), 1970-1975 (Box 92, Folder 689)
    Correspondence, report, bulletin, brochure, news clipping, speech, journal, magazine. Documents in this folder are in English, Portuguese, Spanish and German.
  - General Information - Foreign Investments (Articles), 1960-1974 (Box 93, Folder 690)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, journal, memorandum, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Irrigation, 1966-1969 (Box 94, Folder 691)
    Correspondence, report, photograph, map, memorandum, news clipping, magazine. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Labor (Brochures), 1969 (Box 94, Folder 692)
    Memorandum, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Labor, 1969-1970 (Box 94, Folder 693)
    Correspondence, memorandum, press release, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Corporate Management, 1970 (Box 94, Folder 694)
    Memorandum, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Marketing, 1970-1971 (Box 94, Folder 695)
    Brochure, memorandum, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Marketing - Supermarkets, 1968-1971 (Box 94, Folder 696)
    Correspondence, report, brochure, memorandum, article, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Marketing - Supermarkets, 1956-1973 (Box 94, Folder 697)
    Correspondence, report, telex, brochure, press release, news clipping, news clipping, memorandum, prospectus, annual report. Information about A. C. Nielsen Company. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Marketing - Supermarkets - Boogaarts, 1956-1969 (Box 95, Folder 698, Folder 698A, Folder 698B)
    Correspondence, report, catalogue. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Marketing - Supermarkets - Super Valu Stores, Inc., 1965-1971 (Box 95, Folder 699)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Peruvian Earthquake, 1967-1971 (Box 95, Folder 700)
    Correspondence, article, report, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds (A-L) (Box 96, Folder 701)
  - General Information - Mutual Investment Funds (M-Z) (Box 96, Folder 702)
  - Data and Research - Marketing - Migros Mobile Shops, 1956-1971 (Box 96, Folder 703)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Reports - Thornburg, Max Weston - Middle East, 1947-1950 (Box 96, Folder 704)
    Correspondence, report, cablegram, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Milk, 1947-1969 (Box 96, Folder 705)
    Correspondence, report, brochure, book. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Milk - Foremost Dairies, Inc., 1953-1969 (Box 96, Folder 706)
    Correspondence, news clipping, brochure, report, memorandum, annual report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Data and Research - Milk - H. P. Hood & Sons, 1948-1959 (Box 97, Folder 707)
    Correspondence, brochure, booklet, posters, magazine, memorandum, cablegram, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Marketing - Trading Stamps, 1965-1966 (Box 97, Folder 708)
    Correspondence, memorandum, brochure, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Nationalism, 1969-1971 (Box 97, Folder 709)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, news clipping. Information on Venezuela, Mexico, and Peru. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Oceanography, 1969-1972 (Box 98, Folder 710)
    Correspondence, bulletin, memorandum, report, article, proposal, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - General Information - Population, 1966-1975 (Box 98, Folder 711)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, booklet, bulletin, newsletter, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Potatoes, 1937-1969 (Box 99, Folder 712)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, leaflet, bulletin, journal, article. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - General Information - Poultry, 1972 (Box 99, Folder 713)
    News clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Real Estate Investment Trusts, 1966-1973 (Box 99, Folder 714)
    Correspondence, news clipping, report, press release, annual report, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - General Information - Sea Foods, 1967-1969 (Box 99, Folder 715)
    News clipping, report, leaflet, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Seaweeds, 1969 (Box 99, Folder 716)
  - General Information - Social Responsibility, 1968-1974 (Box 99, Folder 717)
    Correspondence, booklet, article, news clipping, speech, memorandum, report, draft. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Social Responsibility - Reading Articles, 1964-1973 (Box 100, Folder 718)
    Correspondence, article, memorandum, draft, news clipping, journal. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Sociology, 1969-1971 (Box 100, Folder 719)
    Article, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Sociology - Black Community, 1968-1972 (Box 100, Folder 720, Box 101)
    Correspondence, news clipping, directory, book, brochure, report, news clipping, newsletter, memorandum. Information relating to the National Urban League. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Tariffs, 1968-1970 (Box 101, Folder 721)
    Report, article, brochure, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Technical Assistance Information, 1974-1975 (Box 101, Folder 722)
  - General Information - Technological Forecasting, 1970 (Box 101, Folder 723)
    Report, notes. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Urban Affairs, 1962-1970 (Box 101, Folder 724)
    Brochure, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - General Information - Welfare, 1970 (Box 101, Folder 725)
    Magazine. Documents in this folder are in English.
- Conferences, 1951-1976; 6; 5.7 Cubic Feet 15 letter document boxes
  These records include information about conferences relating to subjects that interested IBEC, such as investments abroad and agriculture. Most of the records are in English, but there are some documents in Spanish, Portuguese and French.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the conference.
  - Conferences (A-C), 1958-1976 (Box 101, Folder 726)
    Correspondence, brochure, book, newspaper, article, memorandum, program, newsletter, speech. Note from the IBEC files department: "IBEC had always filed conferences under Data & Research. After the merger with TAOFC and the incorporating of our D&R into their Economic Research, we started filing Conferences under Misc as of July 1966, we began filing conferences in the subject files." Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - Conferences - Association Internationale des Etudiants en Sciences Economiques et Commerciales (AIESEC), 1966-1970 (Box 102, Folder 727)
    Correspondence, brochure, annual report, newsletter, memorandum, program, cablegram, talk. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - Conferences - Columbia University on International Economic Development, 1968-1970 (Box 102, Folder 728)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, program, talk. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences - Columbia University on International Economic Development - Documents, 1970 (Box 102, Folder 729)
    Article, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences (D-G), 1966-1976 (Box 102, Folder 730)
    Correspondence, memorandum, brochure, program. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - Conferences - World Food, 1966-1974 (Box 103, Folder 731)
    Correspondence, news clipping, article, report, program, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences (H-Int), 1958-1974 (Box 103, Folder 732)
    Correspondence, brochure, telegram, program, article, memorandum, news clipping, cablegram, telex. Documents in this folder are in English, Spanish and French.
  - Conferences (Inv-M), 1966-1974 (Box 104, Folder 733)
    Correspondence, program, magazine, memorandum, telex, article, summary, brochure, draft. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United Nations, 1969-1975 (Box 104, Folder 734)
    Correspondence, newsletter, telex, article, directory, newspaper, catalogue. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United Nations Children's Fund, 1969 (Box 104, Folder 735)
  - United Nations Education, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO), 1971 (Box 104, Folder 736)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, speech. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United Nations - Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, 1967-1974 (Box 104, Folder 737)
  - United Nations - Food and Agriculture Organization - Industry - Cooperative Programme, 1966-1976 (Box 105, Folder 738)
    Correspondence, telex, cablegram, summary, memorandum, report, newsletter, press release, program. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United Nations - Food and Agriculture Organization - Industry - Cooperative Programme - Conferences and Sessions, 1966-1976 (Box 105, Folder 739)
    Correspondence, magazine, proposal, telex, draft, report, annual report, program, newsletter, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United Nations - Food and Agriculture Organization - Industry - Cooperative Programme - Protein Food Development, 1972-1974 (Box 106, Folder 740)
    Memorandum, report, brochure, program. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United Nations - General Assembly, 1968 (Box 106, Folder 741)
    Program, memorandum, speech. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United Nations - Panel on Foreign Investment, 1968-1971 (Box 106, Folder 742)
    Correspondence, memorandum, proposal, program, report, news clipping, article. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United Nations - Publications, 1967-1969 (Box 106, Folder 743)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, catalogue, article. Documents in this folder are in English and French.
  - United States Government, 1966-1974 (Box 106, Folder 744)
    Correspondence, memorandum, news clipping, speech. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID), 1961-1971 (Box 107, Folder 745)
    Correspondence, memorandum, news clipping, directory, report, proposal, newsletter, article, speech, telex, cablegram, telegram, newspaper. Documents in this folder are in English and Portuguese.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID) #1, 1965-1968 (Box 107, Folder 746)
    Correspondence, proposal, memorandum, program, catalogue, report, bulletin. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID) #2, 1964-1971 (Box 108, Folder 747)
    Article, bulletin, catalogue, report, press release. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID) - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), 1968-1973 (Box 108, Folder 748)
    Correspondence, report, press release, article, memorandum, summary, speech, balance. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID) - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) - Releases, 1971-1975 (Box 108, Folder 749)
    Press release. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Agency for International Development (AID) - Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC), 1968-1976 (Box 109, Folder 750)
    Correspondence, report, brochure, annual report, newsletter. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Department of Agriculture - Commodity Credit Corporation, 1967-1969 (Box 109, Folder 751)
    Newsletter, report, bulletin, annual report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Balance of Payments, 1959-1968 (Box 109, Folder 752)
    Correspondence, memorandum, balance, brochure, news clippings, bulletin, newsletter. IBEC's reports on balance of payments, Department of Commerce. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Department of Commerce, 1962-1976 (Box 110, Folder 753)
    Correspondence, memorandum, news clipping, speech, booklet, report, summary. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Department of Commerce - National Marketing Advisory Committee, 1966-1969 (Box 110, Folder 754)
    Correspondence, telegram, proposal, minutes, newsletter, memorandum, newspaper, program, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Congress - Legislation, 1971-1975 (Box 110, Folder 755)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, newsletter, summary, news clipping, speech. Equal employment opportunity act - Hartke-Burke Bill- Trade act 1974 - Trade reform act of 1973. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Energy Crisis, 1973-1974 (Box 111, Folder 756)
    Correspondence, article, newsletter, bulletin, report, magazine, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Equity Insurance, 1967 (Box 111, Folder 757)
  - United States Government - 480 Loans, 1956-1970 (Box 111, Folder 758)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, news clipping, bulletin, brochure, news clipping, regulations. Legal information. Documents in this folder are in English and Portuguese.
  - United States Government - 480 Loans - Food for Peace, 1959-1961 (Box 111, Folder 759)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, news clipping, draft, circular. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - House of Representatives - Subcommittee on National Security Policy and Scientific Developments, 1969 (Box 111, Folder 760)
    Correspondence, program, report, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Department of Housing and Urban Development, 1966-1972 (Box 111, Folder 761)
    Correspondence, news clipping, bulletin. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Information Agency, 1966-1970 (Box 111, Folder 762)
    Correspondence, catalogue, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Inter-American Social Development Institute (ISDI), 1970-1971 (Box 112, Folder 763)
  - United States Government - Investment Guarantees, 1951-1974 (Box 112, Folder 764)
    Correspondence, report, application, memorandum, press release, draft, article, news clipping, bulletin, summary, circular, brochure. Information about insurance against commercial and political risk to protect U.S. investors and exporters. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - National Commission on Food Marketing, 1964-1966 (Box 112, Folder 765)
    Correspondence, memorandum, press release, news clipping. Public law information. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Office of Economic Opportunity, 1965-1968 (Box 112, Folder 766)
    Correspondence, directory, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Office of Economic Opportunity - Brochures, 1965-1969 (Box 113, Folder 767)
    Brochures, catalogue, newsletter, manual, program. Information about job opportunities governmental programs. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - President's Advisory Council on Minority Business Enterprise, 1972 (Box 113, Folder 768)
    Correspondence, newspaper. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Private Finance Corp., Undated (Box 113, Folder 769)
  - United States Government - Securities and Exchange Commission, 1968-1976 (Box 113, Folder 770)
    Correspondence, press release, summary, article, brochure, bulletin, memorandum, news clipping, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Department of State, 1969-1975 (Box 113, Folder 771)
    Correspondence, speech, bulletin, news clipping, memorandum, program. Information about trade policy. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - Wage-Price Controls, 1971-1974 (Box 114, Folder 772)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, news clipping, program. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - United States Government - The White House, 1969-1971 (Box 114, Folder 773)
    Correspondence, speech, press release, memorandum, magazine, brochure, application, program. Information about fellows program. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences (N-R), 1964-1976 (Box 114, Folder 774)
    Correspondence, memorandum, program, article, brochure, proposal, report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences (S), 1965-1974 (Box 114, Folder 775)
    Correspondence, memorandum, program, report, article, telex. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Conferences (T-Z), 1964-1976 (Box 115, Folder 776)